const pyq2014=[
    {
    question: "Perspiration is maximum when",
    answers: ["Air is dry and temp is low", "Air is humid and temp is low", "Air is humid and temp is high", " Air is dry and temp is high"],
    correct: "Air is humid and temp is high"
    },
    {
    question: "Which of the following measures the length of a word in computer?",
    answers: ["Micron", "Millimetre", "Metre", "Bits"],
    correct: "Bits"
    },
    {
    question: "A Genetic engineer is",
    answers: ["A engineer interested in Genetics", "A geneticist interested in engineering", "A person who transfers genes from one organism to another", " None of the above"],
    correct: "A person who transfers genes from one organism to another"
    },
    {
    question: "Which one of the following statements is not correct?",
    answers: ["Gobar Gas contains mainly methane", "Cooking gas is a mixture of Butane and Propane", "The I.C chips used in computers are made of Silicon", "Nerve Gas used in chemical warfare is obtained by the action of nitric acid and chloroform"],
    correct: "Nerve Gas used in chemical warfare is obtained by the action of nitric acid and chloroform"
    },
    {
    question: ". Who is the first head of Expenditure Management Commission constituted by central govt in Aug 2014",
    answers: [" Sumit Bose", "Bimal Jalan", "Subeer Gokarna", "Y.S.R Reddy"],
    correct: "Bimal Jalan"
    },
    {
    question: "How many medals India won in 20th Common Wealth Games 2014 held at Glasgow?",
    answers: ["70", "68", "67", "64"],
    correct: "64"
    },
    {
    question: "In the Berlin film festival held in Feb 2014 the golden bear for the best film was given to",
    answers: ["A Royal Affair", "Barbara", "Black Coal Thin Ice", "Just the Wind"],
    correct: "Black Coal Thin Ice"
    },
    {
    question: "Rajiv Gandhi Sadbhavna Award 2014 has been given to",
    answers: ["Sundar Lal Bahuguna", "Anna Hazare", "Muzaffar Ali", "Javed Akhtar"],
    correct: "Muzaffar Ali"
    },
    {
    question: "In which of the following cities f U.S.A is situated Madison Square garden where Indian Prime Minister, Narendra Modi gave his historic speech on 28th Sep 2014",
    answers: ["Washington", "Chicago", "New York", "Boston"],
    correct: "New York"
    },
    {
    question: "Who became the chief minister of Tamilnadu in Sep 2014 after the resignation of J. Jayalalitha",
    answers: ["J Periyakulam", "Y.S Arunachalam", "O. Paneerselvam", "S. Subramaniam"],
    correct: "O. Paneerselvam"
    },
    {
    question: "Who is the writer of the book entitled 'One Life is not Enough : An autobiography' published in Aug 2014",
    answers: ["Manmohan Singh", "Natwar Singh", "Sonia Gandhi", "Lal Krishna Advani"],
    correct: "Natwar Singh"
    },
    {
    question: "Pran Kumar Sharma who died recently in Aug 2014 was a",
    answers: ["Cricketer", "Social Worker", "Environmentalist", "Cartoonist"],
    correct: "Cartoonist"
    },
    {
    question: "As per census of 2011 which of the following states has experienced least population growth in the last decade.",
    answers: ["Mizoram", "Nagaland", "Tamil Nadu", "Kerala"],
    correct: "Nagaland"
    },
    {
    question: "In which of the following states, the President rule was imposed in sep 2014",
    answers: ["Maharashtra", "Nagaland", "Assam", "Kerala"],
    correct: "Maharashtra"
    },
    {
    question: "Which of the following fields was associated B.K.S Iyengar who passed away in Aug 2014",
    answers: ["Yoga", "Education", "Chinema", "Sports"],
    correct: "Yoga"
    },
    {
    question: "Who were jointly declared 'Man of the series' in the international cricket test series played in July/August 2014 between India and England",
    answers: ["James Anderson and John Root", "James Anderson and Bhuvaneshwar Kumar", "John Root and Alistair Cook", ")John Root and M.S Dhoni"],
    correct: "James Anderson and Bhuvaneshwar Kumar"
    },
    {
    question: "The headquarters of small industries development bank of India is situated in",
    answers: ["Ahemadavbad", "Chenni", "Mumbai", "Lucknow"],
    correct: "Lucknow"
    },
    {
    question: "Both the tropic of cancer and tropic of Capricorn pass through",
    answers: ["Asia", "Australia", "South America", "Africa"],
    correct: "Africa"
    },
    {
    question: "Which one of the following district of U.P is not touched by international boundary?",
    answers: ["Balrampur", "Sravasti", "Pilibhit", "Basti"],
    correct: "Sravasti"
    },
    {
    question: "Indian Pulse Research Institute is situated in",
    answers: ["Agra", "Faizabad", "Kanpur", "Jhansi"],
    correct: "Kanpur"
    },
    {
    question: "Under article 267 of Indian constitution provision of which one of the following has been made?",
    answers: ["Consolidated Fund", "Contingency Fund", "Expenditure Fund", "President's Fund"],
    correct: "Contingency Fund"
    },
    {
    question: "Who is the chairman of National Development Council?",
    answers: ["President", "Prime Minister", "Home Minister", "Finance Minister"],
    correct: "Prime Minister"
    },
    {
    question: "Which one of the following is a degradable pollutant?",
    answers: ["Mercury", "Trace Metals", "Domestic Sewage", "Steel"],
    correct: "Domestic Sewage"
    },
    {
    question: "Which one of the following refers to 'Dum Dum' fever?",
    answers: ["Hay Fever", "Kala fever", "Yellow fever", "Scarlet fever"],
    correct: "Kala fever"
    },
    {
    question: "Which of the following is called RDX?",
    answers: ["Cyclo- Trimethyline trinitramine", "Tri- nitrotoluene", "Tri- nitrophenol", "Tri- nitroglycerine"],
    correct: "Cyclo- Trimethyline trinitramine"
    },
    {
    question: "Which of the following gases is used for Bio Terrorism?",
    answers: ["Methane", "Crypton", "Xenon", "Mustard"],
    correct: "Mustard"
    },
    {
    question: "In which of the following the food is not stored in Tap Roots?",
    answers: ["Carrot", " Sweet Potato", "Sugarbeet", "Turnip"],
    correct: " Sweet Potato"
    },
    {
    question: "Gossamer Silk is produced by",
    answers: ["Silk worm", "Spider", "Tussar Moth", "Scorpion"],
    correct: "Spider"
    },
    {
    question: "Which of the following vitamins is water soluble?",
    answers: [" Vit A", " Vit D", " Vit C", " Vit E"],
    correct: " Vit C"
    },
    {
    question: "Human sterility is caused mainly due to deficiency of",
    answers: ["Fats", "Proteins", " Folic Acid", "Vitamin E"],
    correct: "Vitamin E"
    },
    {
    question: "Bolometer is a device to measure",
    answers: ["Pressure", "Growth in Plants", "Thermal Radiation", "Speed of wind"],
    correct: "Thermal Radiation"
    },
    {
    question: "In which of the following regimes, the 'rolling plan' was introduced in India?",
    answers: ["Congress Regime", "NDA Regime", "Janta Party Regime", "UPA Regime"],
    correct: "Janta Party Regime"
    },
    {
    question: "Under which of the following articles of Constitution, National Emergency can be proclaimed by the president of India?",
    answers: ["Article-352", "Article-356", "Article-358", "Article-360"],
    correct: "Article-352"
    },
    {
    question: "Which one of the following is not mentioned in the preamble of the Indian Constitution?",
    answers: ["Sovereign", "Socialist", "Republic", "Federal"],
    correct: "Federal"
    },
           
]